<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>lysts - notes</title><link href="https://lysts.xyz/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://lysts.xyz/feeds/notes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://lysts.xyz/</id><updated>2023-07-30T19:01:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Newb to Code, Newb to Climbing</title><link href="https://lysts.xyz/keeping-active.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-30T19:01:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-30T19:01:00+01:00</updated><author><name>lysts</name></author><id>tag:lysts.xyz,2023-07-30:/keeping-active.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;keeping active, challenging a new sport, how it plays into my journey
with programming&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="contents topic" id="table-of-contents"&gt;
&lt;p class="topic-title"&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#to-be-spent-and-to-be-protected" id="toc-entry-1"&gt;To be spent and to be protected&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#mobility-habits-of-choice" id="toc-entry-2"&gt;Mobility habits of choice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#the-recent-addition" id="toc-entry-3"&gt;The recent addition!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference internal" href="#mobility-habits-code" id="toc-entry-4"&gt;Mobility Habits &amp;amp; Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="to-be-spent-and-to-be-protected"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#toc-entry-1"&gt;To be spent and to be protected&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health. It's pretty easy to fall into the habit of taking our health for granted
(guilty as charged)... Getting into healthy habits takes time and we
often put it off pointing out that single piece of pizza, losing heat at the
intersection of four relatively hungry friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though blatantly obvious, it's sometimes difficult to remind ourselves of how
that beautifully refreshing and invigorating exercise euphoria feels. Not only
that, but improved physical and mental strength, like when you climb up a
flight of stairs and realise that that core strengthening exercise really paid
off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albeit this blog serving as a reminder laundry bag to myself, take or leave as many tokens as
you'd like; here are some of my mobility habits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mobility-habits-of-choice"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#toc-entry-2"&gt;Mobility habits of choice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Yoga
This has been a constant hell yes in my repertoire. What I love about it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;requires just a mat, some space, and you of course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take it outdoors or indoors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make it solo or social&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plethora of moves, flows, variations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decompresses, twists, challenges and relaxes the body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, you can identify your needs, chop up a sequence, stich em up together by choice
and there you go, your perfect regimen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ease into building mind-to-muscle connections with intention. A simple flow can
help you stretch and awaken muscles throughout your entire body in your
mornings. A more intense session can make you sweat, really engage your
core, build muscle anywhere you desire, and improve your flexiibility,
simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Pilates
I see this as an extension of yoga, where you...:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take those muscles and really target them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;core building. yes, it can burn (good burns)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evokes a good sweat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;again, you only really need a mat, some space, and you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- FORM is crucial in both practices so practice attentiveness to where
your limbs are placed, movements, and your posture --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Running
This is perhaps more commercial so I won't delve but I suppose I'll touch on
some struggles I've had to leave some pointers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not pacing myself properly —› start small, even if it feels easy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;long-term consistency —› timeblock in your schedule, find a friend to run with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;post-exercise coughing —› keep walking outside whilst you cool down (avoid sitting straight down in a badly ventilated indoor space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tennis &amp;amp; Football:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stress relieving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;satisfying to smash/kick a ball&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;game element, strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;involves both running and staying still, mix of stillness and running&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've oftentimes enjoyed such sport after a long day of work, or at the end
of the week on weekends. It can be rewarding to practice precision, the types of ways you can serve or return the ball to achieve a
pre-determined trajectory or tactic. It really works your arms and legs and
reflexiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-recent-addition"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#toc-entry-3"&gt;The recent addition!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Climbing (bouldering)
So far, each time I've climbed, I've gone with an experienced climber. Each time,
I have noticed that they move with smoothness and reduced inefficient movement
and tension. It's mesmerising to watch, and I've come to appreciate the sport
as an art form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be one of the most challenging sports I've ever done. Don't be
deceived by the height of the walls that only seem to last a few meters...
There are varying levels of difficulty for every climber. Quick overview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bouldering walls have colour coded grips that belong to different paths of distinguished levels. Start hands are often labelled for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once you reach the top and final grip, both hands must meet the grip together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can use any grip from any path on the way down, or jump from a reasonable
height (don't worry, the floor is well cushioned...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sport gets you out of your comfort zone, testing your grip, toes, agility,
back and arms — practically everything. It requires a lot of planning and
strategy, and at times trial and error to figure out different paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With it, your mental strength and stamina are put to the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be discouraging when you can't make it to the top in one go (a &amp;quot;flash&amp;quot;).
You may feel vulnerable, &amp;quot;failing&amp;quot; in front of other observing climbers.
Whilst you're climbing, you may panic due to the sheer height, tense up, or feel like your arms are giving out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But learning that...:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there's no time limit. Take your time solving a path, or move on to others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it's okay to turn back and fall, you can always try again, today or another day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other climbers are always friendly, non-judgemental, and willing to help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this becomes good practice of failure, challenging and believing in yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perseverance becomes resilience — you become less fear-ridden with time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has honestly led to immense self-growth in a short amount of time:):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
Just yesterday, I went climbing, and felt proud of myself when I managed to clear
a path I thought I wouldn't manage. I felt stuck 80% of the way up and had to rest
about 3-4 meters above ground due to muscle fatigue.
But after giving myself a moment, I pushed myself up to the last grip. And boy,
was it undeniably satisfying.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mobility-habits-code"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a class="toc-backref" href="#toc-entry-4"&gt;Mobility Habits &amp;amp; Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With programming, you always meet a multitude of debugging issues. Just like a grip that may
have been out of sight, you may have missed something so blatantly obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be frustrating (in my case, I end up hysterically laughing). It's
discouraging when things don't quite work. But similarly to yoga and climbing,
you make attempts, you see improvement, you reach higher and you push yourself
incrementally. The way you address problem solving may become more precise and
efficient as you unlock thought processes and improve the quality of your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, simple code is the best code. You don't want to overcomplicate or
overwork your muscle movements, you want them to support your objectives.
Similarly, your code should be there to help you accomplish your goals, not
diminish them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These habits have and hopefully will continue to feed in to my journey with
programming in a symbiotic manner. Timeblocking periods of exercise into my
schedule has improved my concentration and sleep quality, and diminished that
mental block to simply do things and get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="notes"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="mind"></category><category term="sport"></category></entry><entry><title>neat crumbs</title><link href="https://lysts.xyz/neat-crumbs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-12T19:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-12T19:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>lysts</name></author><id>tag:lysts.xyz,2023-07-12:/neat-crumbs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;random knick-knacks, phrases&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="text-to-art-generators"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;text to art generators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;figlet, brew install and throw in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="referring-to-the-general-public-genderless-ver"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;referring to the general public (genderless ver.)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ladles and jellyspoons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="english-is-a-weird-language"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;english is a weird language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cursory look&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="notes"></category><category term="arbitrary"></category><category term="fun"></category></entry><entry><title>setting up github actions for pelican</title><link href="https://lysts.xyz/github-actions-pelican.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-07-08T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-08T11:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>lysts</name></author><id>tag:lysts.xyz,2023-07-08:/github-actions-pelican.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;web-building with github actions and pelican&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first attempt was to try and make a yml file to do github actions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="notes"></category><category term="github"></category></entry></feed>